

Paolo Cattaneo

Software Engineer

CONTACTS

3404834985

paolo.cattaneo92@gmail.com

paolo.cattaneo92@gmail.com
https://paolocattaneo92.github.io/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/paolo-cattaneo-eng/

Binasco (Milan)

PROFILE

I am a passionate Software Engineer, devoted to Software Design & Development, with experience in the *RTLS*, *IoT* and *Industry 4.0* worlds.

I have a specific interest in the *Backend* world but during my professional experience I've always covered a *Full stack* role. I swim almost smoothly inside the *Microsoft* environment (.NET Framework, .NET Core, C#, WPF, SQL Server). My goal is to never stop getting *better* and learning *new* instruments, technologies and contexts.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE



Software Engineer JAN 2019 – Now Milan Various projects as Full stack Software Engineer, designing and developing software solutions with complex architectures and multiple actors, one of them being the main product of Ubiquicom.

Tags: RTLS, IoT, Industry 4.0, BLE, UWB .Net Framework, WPF, .Net Core, software on Raspberry, MySQL, SQL Server, API, REST, MQTT, Protocol buffer, ZeroMQ



Consulting Software Engineer NOV 2018 – JAN 2019 Milan Refactoring and modernization of the whole web Backend ecosystem of Allianz.

Tags: Java, Backend development, Spring, Maven, Orika, SQL Server, REST API.



Software Engineer OCT 2017 – OCT 2018 Gorgonzola (Milan) Internship and stage. Design and development of multiple internal tools for satellite mass memory testing phases.

Tags: C#, WPF, .NET Framework, MongoDB, Python, Backend and Desktop development

I authorize the processing of my personal data pursuant to Legislative Decree 30 June 2003, n. 196 "Code regarding the protection of personal data".

EDUCATION

Master Degree in Computer Engineering – Laurea magistrale in Ingegneria Informatica

On March 2018, at *Università degli Studi di Bergamo*.

Thesis: "3D4Amb-ULib: Design and Development of a Unity3D library for amblyopia therapy with VR games"

Bachelor Degree in Computer Engineering – Laurea Triennale in Ingegneria Informatica

On March 2015, at Università degli Studi di Bergamo.

Thesis: "Design and Development of an Android application for stereoacuity test using anaglyphic Randots"

Diploma di Liceo Scientifico

On June 2011, at Istituto Superiore D.M. Turoldo di Zogno (Bergamo)

LANGUAGES

Language	Written	Speech
English	C1	C1
French	A2	A2

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Worked for a top Italian RTLS company: expert in localization technologies with GPS, BLE and UWB.
 Certifications with partners that are world leader in RTLS and IoT world.
- Focus on Backend development technologies in C#.
- Intermediate level of Frontend development with WPF and Material Design.
- Knowledge of .NET Framework 4.6.1+. Multiplatform projects developed with .NET Core 3, deployed on Windows/Linux/ARM (Raspberry PI4).
- Design and development of RESTful Web APIs with ASP.NET.
- Retrieval and manipulation of data in database (MySQL/SQL Server/MongoDB) and file (CSV, JSON, YAML, XML).
- Development tools: Visual Studio 2019, Git, Postman.
- Others: UML, Microsoft Windows 10, Android, Office 365.

SOFT SKILLS

- Great motivation to grow up professionally and learn fast. Goal oriented approach.
- Good communicative skills, public speech.
- Team building and self-work autonomy. Doing my best when I am under a deadline pressure (useful when it is the daily normality).
- Commonly people love to work with me because of my light nature and positive vibes.
- Patience and always ready to listen other people opinions with a constructive attitude.